<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>James Minton</title>
        <link>https://jamesminton.com/</link>
        <description>Recent content on James Minton</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 17:27:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesminton.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Mysterious Allure of the Baroque Internet Scam</title>
        <link>https://jamesminton.com/p/the-mysterious-allure-of-the-baroque-internet-scam/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 17:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jamesminton.com/p/the-mysterious-allure-of-the-baroque-internet-scam/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With all due sympathies for those on the receiving end, I do get a ton of enjoyment from learning about  bizarre internet scams (a niche but growing true crime subgenre). The best hook is when some sort of foul play is clearly happening, but the motivation, monetization strategy, and endgame are all far from evident, leaving space wide open for speculation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the latest one from the New York Times: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/21/books/publishing-manuscripts-phishing-scam.html?referringSource=articleShare&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Why on Earth Is Someone Stealing Unpublished Book Manuscripts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Hannaham was just one of countless targets in a mysterious international phishing scam that has been tricking writers, editors, agents and anyone in their orbit into sharing unpublished book manuscripts. It isn’t clear who the thief or thieves are, or even how they might profit from the scheme. High-profile authors like Margaret Atwood and Ian McEwan have been targeted, along with celebrities like Ethan Hawke. But short story collections and works by little-known debut writers have been attacked as well, even though they would have no obvious value on the black market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the manuscripts do not appear to wind up on the black market at all, or anywhere on the dark web, and no ransoms have been demanded. When copies of the manuscripts get out, they just seem to vanish. So why is this happening?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides mysterious motives, another intriguing feature is the byzantine nature of some of these operations. For instance, I manage website analytics for several sites, and used to receive tons of referral traffic (inbound links from external websites) from fake internet properties. I&amp;rsquo;d click on the referrer in the analytics dashboard, expecting to see a news article or blog linking to the site I manage, only be taken to a (definitely malware-ridden) page hawking the spam du jour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To walk through the scheme: someone set up a fake website with links to mine, banking that I would know my way around an analytics dashboard, find it in the referrers list, and be lured to click—a number of links in a chain of unlikely occurrences culminating in a low-probability outcome. Then somewhere down the line &amp;hellip; profit. Of course all of this is automated and relatively low-effort, but still a reminder of the levels of imagination that can be deployed just for clicks. And to the scammer&amp;rsquo;s credit, it worked, at least partially. Maybe at scale and in a country with a favorable exchange rate, this is someone&amp;rsquo;s decent-paying hustle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last, lesser-discussed feature, the one that grips me the most: the sometimes-surreal beauty of these scams&#39; outward forms—almost always unintentional, as the motive is seldom anything other than profit. But occasionally you see the same phenomenon as when, say, an intricate machine designed purely for function&amp;rsquo;s sake accidentally becomes a work of art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Case in point: my favorite Reply All episode, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gimletmedia.com/shows/reply-all/n8ho3a&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Case of the Phantom Caller&lt;/a&gt;, wherein an elaborate phone scam generates—almost as an incidental side effect—an unnerving &amp;ldquo;found audio&amp;rdquo; collage resembling a Burroughs-style cut-up piece, not unlike a lot of the experimental music I listened to in college. Oddly, the hosts spend most of the time examining the complex mechanics of this long-distance fraud, but very little marveling at its curious auditory fruits. Both of these combined make for an hour-long WTF? that still haunts me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/33600899056_702eb90042_k.jpg" alt="Featured image of post " /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Very random sample of some of my photos: swimming off the coast of Maui with a cheap underwater camera, looking out the window of the Met Breuer, a blizzard on the Lower East Side.
&lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37608895574_e8c04b5e52_o.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;2929x1953&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37608895574_e8c04b5e52_o_hu2e2fceec45129f76ea8ceab18827829c_6040562_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37608895574_e8c04b5e52_o_hu2e2fceec45129f76ea8ceab18827829c_6040562_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37608895574_e8c04b5e52_o.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2929&#34; height=&#34;1953&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;&amp;nbsp;&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt; &lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37442715464_7c71abdfe6_k.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;2047x1365&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37442715464_7c71abdfe6_k_hud8ec51d86d969592dcb8684dcade0a89_746223_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37442715464_7c71abdfe6_k_hud8ec51d86d969592dcb8684dcade0a89_746223_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/37442715464_7c71abdfe6_k.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2047&#34; height=&#34;1365&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;&amp;nbsp;&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;  &lt;figure&gt;
		&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/33600899056_702eb90042_k.jpg&#34; data-size=&#34;2048x1367&#34;&gt;
			&lt;img srcset=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/33600899056_702eb90042_k_hu4dae86ed196205a7be5431ac29ab4569_632831_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/33600899056_702eb90042_k_hu4dae86ed196205a7be5431ac29ab4569_632831_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
				src=&#34;https://jamesminton.com/p/photo-gallery/33600899056_702eb90042_k.jpg&#34; width=&#34;2048&#34; height=&#34;1367&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
				alt=&#34;&amp;nbsp;&#34;&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
		
	&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
